Hello, were live and build and we're talking to some awesome developers why
don't you guys introduce yourselves and...a little bit about what you...yeah,
I'm jason davis...steve...fantastic intel's...
we built the microsoft movie crater in a nutshell what is it
well our goal in building microsoft movie creator...the to give users the ability to create a
five-minute movie in about five minutes make it's stupid simple makes what we cut a lot of video
channelized it can't be that simple do you have something to show us...sort of an overview of what's going on
Without those...
...for me so many ways.
...I...today.
...different boards for different waves.
...like moi.
Two or three-years-old.
I remember one...
...miserable consumer use their theme came out
and push me...waves...the feeling...I first run away...
...my new player.
Grown-up and my dad and fixing cars we always did everything himself
To be successful.
Do something and, that's so awesome
about making surfboard making things that people have fun...
Another everything about surfing.
From the air.
...you can say well.
Samoa.
So, that's a really cool application you have like a little demo you...just absolutely.
So, this is the.
Essentially what you do is you...you can choose videos photos you can also
...stuff organized by location you can even connector one drive account all
...cool and grab your photos and videos from there...already picked a bunch of stuff here.
And, you can.
Most people just start to watch their movie that
the main thing is people want to put something together very quickly and, then get into all of the different
editing options so here is rendering out natural movie for playback I'm not going to
play I'm actually go back and show you some of the other things that you can do okay
so you can, for example, drag-and-drop clips around and change the order of stuff.
You can add titles.
And, this is a new feature in this release
...change fawn change color change the position of
the titles on-screen change the size of them as well you can
going to individual clip so that's going to this individual video clip and as options to
...captions on top of it, for example,...
You can apply filter
...just that one clip you can do some different rotate functions you
can pan zoom in like you can burns effect so...it you we all take videos
...pictures all the time now we can sort of spits them together to something that's pretty cool absolutely,
absolutely and the goal here was to make something aesthetically beautiful very quickly you
don't and you don't have to use all
of these editing features the way we do this to make something good quick is we
have themes dot...we have movie same so the outcomes with a handful of themes built-in.
You pick a theme...the theme basically has all of the creative decision-making for you
got what filter to apply what's the duration of each
...how it transitions from
...seem to etc and if you don't like any of these
themes you can hit up the theme store and download new themes vr in...
team store and that's really that's really cool for me because I'm not very artistic so it's really nice to have
someone make the artistic decisions it's fantastic so what kind of devices is this
available, yeah, so, it's available for all the surface tablets...well as the
looming tablets and the entire range of
...devices from all the way from like five-thirty all the way
to the visit fifteen twenty well that's awesome is how do so you're of the...side
...the engineering side how do you make all of this work?
For all of the devices...you tell me a layout of the project how it set up well, there's a couple.
Elements to that one there's the user interface right you have to make it work on something that's
as big as the surface...and, something that's down the small size of like that
right five-thirty of their so we spend a lot of time this is more
...side in the designer side to make a ui that's
flexible enough to work on a big high-end device and then also work
...small and you can still use all the controls functionally on the...devices...what is
a redman diaspora, yeah, of course so the user interface is csharp
and's animal fantastic and then underneath that we have the rendering engine which
is the part that takes all your video clips all your edit decisions and all the
sort of the set of rules from the theme you picked format takes all that footage in...
your final video and that's written in cplus-plus on top of media
foundation indirect to the just using public widely available microsoft
api us that's really cool because you're actually doing some pretty heavy computation on
a tiny device as I think it's really cool that you're able to leverage the cplus-plus direct
...up and for the design and layout using examines csharp.
What is your project look like you have to create a project
...project for each type of device or is there
...example helps you sort of fit into all of...devices...this thing you might have heard of
...called the universal project nice...universal windows platform right,
yeah, so, how does that help you work with all
of these devices well, makes it nice because we have a single code base...you know,
I mean I'd be lying if I said there were a couple if that's in there the for the lower and
while for the windows versus the phone the absolute projectsand,
then we do have to do some things for the lower
memory devices where we have to sort of limit output resolutions you can have, you know, you have a high-end
phone can shoot four-k video...you're not going to get that on the five-to-one,...
it's but, still, you know, using the same code base we can make a
project works on that five twenty pretty much with any video footage you can...on
that device you just can download your four-k video from the internet
It seems like it like when you're
going through the technical design process do you have to think about every divisor
...universal windows platform...help you abstract away or is there discussion about these
things, you know, pretty much abstracted away there's?
Very little thought we have no more designing the whole application as
...you know, the capabilities of...places are not it's more like
...are design where we have to make sure it's going to the
...design ui going to scale to both form factors mn there's more
just performance issues that we have to address when they come up with...devices
that's really cool so let's take a step back what was your inspiration for making this up you know,
my backgrounds in computing in the arts and film and video and I've grew up skateboarding
...making my own home movies and sharing that with my family and,
even today now that I have kids I want to make stuff and send that to grandma and,
you know, obviously you can spend five hours making...movie,...on done that
...and that's a lot of time to invest so we wanted to make something that you
could make that five-minute movie and just five minutes that means taking away a lot of the
decision-making wrapping that up in these themes and, simple finite to
...footage watch it like...go with...makes it and then make some
...changes...you want to make.
That's fantastic so there's nothing more satisfying than for developer to
make something that people use tell me what's the reaction
been so far on this application really good so we launched movie creator as a beta
is still...back in november two thousand fourteen we're averaging about
hundred-thousand downloads among
while four-and-a-half star rating as we've also got a beta feedback
email address built into the app so you can go to the information tab email
us directly give us feature requests tell us what we're doing right what we're doing wrong and,
then we've actually inc a lot of the feedback that we've gotten since november
...the release that's going it should be live now in the store as of this morning we published this morning
but some new features well that's awesome any anything we could do to
learn more about this work and people go name et cetera actually the beta feedback
email addresses probably the best place to give
us direct feedback and you'll find there's some support
sites the on microsoft-dot-com if you have any support questions
other than that I would I would encourage you to go to the store download the app and start playing with all right
...thanks so much for spending some time as any parting words for viewers.
On co-author make some good videos and
...is the...on will thanks so much for watching and we'll see you next time take care.